Guide to the Theodore John Kreps Papers
Stanford University Libraries.
- Papers
  - 1944 August-September (Box 11, Folder 61)
    Industrial diamonds; Suisse pour Valeurs Metaux Pirelli; Chromite Automobiles; I.G. Farben; Sieve -furnaces; Societe General; National Product; Argentina - Defense Supply Corporation, living conditions, import & export, political platform, production foodstuffs, sulphur, facsist propoganda & organization, labor; Aircraft manufacture & service; Industrial diamonds; German firms' American connections; Gyroscope; IT & T; Cocoa - Africa; Philips Company; Proclaimed & statutory lists; Iron & Steel - German cartels; Webb-Pomerene - export trade.
  - 1944 October (Box 11, Folder 62)
    FEA director - Conf. Bolivian Uranian Tungsten Mine; Trademark; Patents; SKF - bearings; Surplus War Property.
  - 1944 October (Box 12, Folder 63)
    German Economic Warfare; Inflation - Greece; Surplus property disposal; Property of U.S. - Austrian A.B. Svenska Mullagerfabriken (SKF)
  - 1944 November-December (Box 12, Folder 64)
    SKF; World Week - Russia; Electrical; Elektroholm; A.B.; Rayon; Surplus property disposal; German industrialists - plans for underground activity; Profiteering; Cartels & National Security; International Commodity Agreements; Webb-Pomerene; Industrial Diamonds; Shipping.
  - 1944 n.d. (Box 12, Folder 65)
    Air Transport Policy - International; Canada, Royal Bank cf; Cartels - international airline pools general; Copper - postwar Europe; Drugs - Patents; FEA blockade of Germany; Nicaro nickel in Cuba, programs; Free Enterprise and Government; Merchant Marine; Patents - science & monopoly; Railroads -anti-trust; Steel: Sulpher & sulphuric acid; Titanium.
  - 1944 n.d. (Box 12, Folder 66)
  - 1944 January-February (Box 12, Folder 67)
    Voorhis Bill, H.R., 97 - anti-trust; Profiteering - Littell; Public Education bill s. 181; Public Health Service Act amendment s. 191; Phosphate; Cartel memo - Convention on Restrictive Trade Practices; Patents; Electrical; Industrial Diamonds; Colombia Valley Authority bill s. 460; Postwar stockpiles; Cartels; Missouri Valley Authority a. 555; Fair Employment Practices bill H.R. 2232; Axel Wenner - Gren's interests; Electrical.
  - 1944 March (Box 13, Folder 68)
    Rubber - synthetic & natural; Sulphur; Government Corporations; Cartels - French, Safehaven report; Patents - bill H.R. 2612; Farben; Aircraft Surplus- rental for commercial use; Cartels - restrictive governmental agreements & arrangements on manufactured products; Chemicals, Drugs & Pharmaceuticals; Economic conditions; Postwar Trade - U.S. & U.S.S.R.
  - 1945 April (Box 13, Folder 69)
    Societe Generale; IT& T - interests in German Electrical. I.G. Farben industrie, A.G. - guide for investigation; Taxation; Machine tools.
  - 1945 May-June (Box 13, Folder 70)
    Tin - Bolivia; Sweden -Wallenberg's control of economy; IT & T; Canada; Stockpiling; Electrical; Aviation gasoline; Chemicals, etc.; International Trade Tribunal; Southern U.S. - health; Transportation - antitrust; Cartels - plastic - German patents; Iron & Steel - war plants disposal (T. letter stamped Joseph C. Mahoney); Kilgore Corn. - subcommittee on war mobilization; External Security Program (regarding Farben); Spain, Bank of; War Productic: WPB index.
  - 1945 July-Decenber (Box 13, Folder 71)
    Inflation & Deflation; IT & T; Selected Subcommittee Docs. - index; bill a. 1297 for National Science Foundation; Removing Wartime Economic Controls - international aspects; Thomas Jefferson (inscribed by author, George Fort Milton); A New Economic Order; Patents; Borax; Chemicals, etc.; Tariff reduction; Socialized Medicine; The Hotel Industry; Drugs & Pharmaceuticals; Control of I.G. Farben - Military Government. of Germany; Canada & International Cartels; Labor - take-home pay; Reconversion; Webb-Pomerene (TLS Edward S. Mason).
  - 1945 n.d.-1946 February (Box 13, Folder 72)
    Cartels - & enemy property; China Trade; Electrical; Industrialization of South; Machine Tools surplus; Stockpiling; Webb-Pomerene (TLS Morris Rosenthal, Fritz Machlup); Patents; Water & Power California; Labor - wages; Standards of Living; Cartel control; Bendix Aviation - Patents, etc.
  - 1946 March-n.d. (Box 13, Folder 73)
    Webb-Pomerene; Nationalists - American Action Company clips; Electrical & Glass; "The Commununist in Labor Relations Today;" Coal - anti-trust; Nickel; International Communications Merger; Anti-trust. - Pacific Coast - European Conf. - Maritime Commission; USSR; Monopoly & Foreign U.S. Communication; Soil Conservation; Bullion & Gold-Silver Ratio; Canada & U.S.; Consumer education; International ~Trade Organization; Labor - Management; International Trade Disputes - arbitration; Minimum Wage; U.S. Prices v Soviet Bargains.
  - 1947 (Box 14, Folder 74)
    Unconditional Most-Favored-Nation Policy; Trends of Corporate Mergers & Acquisitions; California Farm Reporter; Rent Control; Cartels & Combines in Occupied Areas; Fire Equipment; Military Tribunals Case No. 6. - Nuremberg War Crimes case against I.G. Farben officials; Agriculture - Schultz' analysis & policy proposals; Medical Care; U.S. Foreign Policy - Far East; Business standards; Reconstruction of Europe; International Cartels; National Debt.
  - 1948 (Box 14, Folder 75)
    German decartelization - Military Government; Bosch Combine; United Nations principles & Labor; Price fixing - optical; Standard Oil of California - antitrust; Survey of Consumer Finances; Cartel - International Electrical Equipment; Canada's Natural Resources; Pipe - anti-trust; Nickel - anti-trust; United States Lines et al - anti-trust; Cable -anti-trust; Basing points - steel; Power Irrigation & Flood Control Projects; World's Food; European Recovery & Free Labor; International Business Organization - postwar trends.
  - 1949 (Box 14, Folder 76)
    Trupp - Military Tribunal Nuremberg Case No. 10 Property confiscation; Workers' Buying Power; Conservation - forests; Corporate Profits; Risk Capital Germany - Decartelization & deconcentration; Government subsidies; Optical - anti-trust; Conservation & Utilization of Resources; Medical Economics; Socialists in America.
  - l950, capital formation. (Box 14, Folder 77)
    Taft-Hartley; Methodism's Pink Fringe?; Income payments vs. Price supports; Prevent World War III; James Stewart (John Earl Ferguson) - Harry Bridges and Communism; Communism; Big Business; Economic Progress- Primary Products; Optical - anti-trust; Korea, etc & Soviet policy; Tin-Pan Alley monopoly; Business
  - 1951-1952 (Box 15, Folder 78)
    Wage stabilization & Inflation; Price control rationing of meat; Market explanaion under mobilization; Productive capacity, use of; Peace Offensive -investments; Inventories - Key Business Problem -Budget Cutting; Communism vs. Democracy In Near East; Lecture outlines - Credit Controls, Inflation, International Political situation & effects on U.S.; Gold in Modern Economy; Du Pont - "The Story ox' Research; European Recovery Program - Commodity Report; Resale Price Maintenance.
  - 1953 (Box 15, Folder 79)
    Restrictive Business Practices; [80] Legal sources for study of Anti-trust laws; Bibliographies - Legal & economic concepts, Foreign Trade, Administration & Enforcement; Standard Oil of New Jersey; Basic Miners Resources.
  - 1953 (Box 15, Folder 80)
  - 1954-1962 (Box 15, Folder 81)
    Government competition;_Anti-trust Bulletin Electrical anti-trust; Cellophane Anti-trust Case; Punched Lard Accounting - MBA; Depletion - oil & gas wells; Honey Creation; Credit Expansion & Interest Rates; Big Corporation - where its money goes; Tensions; Percentage Depletion; Pooled Money Investment; Pacific Finance Corp.; Railway Age; U.S. Steel Quarterly, The Humble Way; John Deere; Economic forecast; Prudential Insurance
  - n.d. (includes fragment.) (Box 15, Folder 82)
    American-Soviet Relations; Axel Werner-Gren; German cartels - charts, decision, analysis; Rubber; French Africa - economic aid; Government aid; Optical; Belgium -economic development; Conservat1on; Glass; Milk; Dollar; Soil; Standardization - testing materials; Lost Monopolies; American Shipping; Pacific Northwest Rayon Industry; Dangers of American Fascism; Dyestuffs
  - Cartels- 1, 1921-1961 (Box 16, Folder 83)
    List of International Cartels in 1939 (1944), Outline of Proposed International Trade Organization (n.d.), U.S. Government Loans to Private Corps, involved in Restrictive Trade Practices in International Trade (n.d.); List of Cartel Memoranda (1944); Germany -re: book about Farben (1946), Germany & Enlarged Dye Cartel (1932, s. by Sydney B. Redecker), Use of Cartels in Heavy Industry (1943); O'Mahoney Bill (1945); Cartel clips. etc. (1944 & n.d.) & memo re: Combined Boards (1944) & Cartel memo 107 (19145); Dynamics of German Cartels & Patents (n.d.)
  - Cartels - 2, 1921-1961 (Box 16, Folder 84)
    Dyes & Dyestuffs - British report (1921); Outline for Cartel Study - Possible contents of hearings on Concentration, Control & Cartelization of U.S. Copper Industry (1935-45); mostly general atudies & correspondence.
  - Cartels - 3, 1921-1961 (Box 16, Folder 85)
    Brazilian Industry & the War, Moroccan Groupements International Commodity Organization, International Cartel Policy, Agreements, Registration & Control, Bolivia Gustaf Thain, Norwegian law, Britain, FEA policy (1939-1414); Webb-Pomerene (1935); foreign Trade Work (1938); Cartels & Business Crisis (1931); Cartelization of England (n. d.); German Cartel Policy (1933), Maps (1938).
  - Cartels - 4, 1921-1961 (Box 16, Folder 86)
    Legal Position of --- in Europe (l938); Analysis of Collective Monopolies in Europe (1935); Modern Industrial Organization (n.d.); International Cartels (n.d.); Locations & types (1931); German Cartel Problems (n.d.); Cartel system - Its Future (n.d.); Significance For American Business (1944); -----Postwar World (1943); pamphlets (l944, 1945); Controlling World Trade (1947); Electrical Equipment Anti-trust Cases (1961); Combines Investigation Act (1961).
  - Magnesium in the Pacific Northwest ca. 1938-l947, (Found in one special folder, order maintained-). Reports, surveys, legal proceedings, etc. re: magnesium industry - sources, uses, etc. (Box 16, Folder 87)
  - Magnesium in the Pacific Northwest ca. 1938-l947, (Found in one special folder, order maintained-). Reports, surveys, legal proceedings, etc. re: magnesium industry - sources, uses, etc. (Box 16, Folder 88)
- Additional papers, Accession ARCH-2015-023
  - Correspondence
    Approximately 400 original letters, mostly manuscript, from Theodore to his wife, Esther, which the former was away (mostly) in Washington DC, circa 1952-1960, with much correspondence during the periodwhen he was Director the Congress's Joint Committee on the Economic Report (during the Eisenhower years). Also includes correspondence to Kreps from other writers.
    - Collection of letters from former students and associates written in celebration of 80th birthday celebration, 1976-11-13; 1 album(s) (Box 1)
      A COLLECTION OF LETTERS from former students & associates written with affection and respectfor Theodore & Esther Kreps in celebration of his 80th birthday. The Graduate School of Business, Stanford University, is also proud to announce the establishment of a fund in their honor to be known as the Theodore J.& Esther Kreps Fellowship. Alumni Day, November 13,1976. Thick folio (14 in.) with160 original manuscript andtyped letter, honoring the couple—and especially Krebs as a teacher at the Stanford School of Business, from former student... from Ernest Arbuckle (then Chairman of Wells Fargo Bank) to Wayne Zook. This volume oflettersfrom former studentsand colleague collectively provides much insight, and manyanecdotes, to Kreps' long tenure on the Stanford faculty.
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Dec. 1966, 1966 Dec (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Nov 1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Feb 1958 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps 1958 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Oct 1966, 1966 Oct (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Mar-Dec 1959, 1959 Mar-Dec (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Feb 1959, 1959 Feb (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Jan 1959, 1959 Jan (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Mar 1958, 1958 Mar (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Jan 1958, 1958 Jan (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps 1957 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Dec 1956, 1956 Dec (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Mar 1956, 1956 Mar (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Feb 1956, 1956 Feb (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Jan 1956, 1956 Jan (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Dec 1955, 1955 Dec (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Sept 1955, 1955 Sept (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Jun 1955, 1955 Jun (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps May 1955, 1955 May (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Apr 1955, 1955 Apr (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps 1953 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Mar 1952, 1952 Mar (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Feb 1952, 1952 Feb (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps 1951 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Mar 1951, 1951 Mar (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Feb 1951 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Jan 1951, 1951 Jan (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Dec 1950, 1950 Dec (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps May 1950, 1950 May (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Apr 1950 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Feb 1950, 1950 Feb (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Jan 1950, 1950 Jan (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Dec 1949, 1949 Dec (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Mar 1949, 1949 Mar (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Feb 1949, 1949 Feb (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Jan 1949, 1949 Jan (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Dec 1948, 1948 Dec (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Sept 1948, 1948 Sept (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Mar 1948, 1948 Mar (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Jan 1948, 1948 Jan (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Jan 1947, 1947 Jan (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Aug 1946, 1946 Aug (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps Jul 1946, 1946 Jul (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - To: Esther E. Kreps From: Theodore Kreps May 1944, 1944 May (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - To: Dr. Kreps 1943 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - To: Dr. and Mrs. Kreps 1933 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Misc. Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Misc. Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Misc. Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Photographs (Box 3)
      Photograph albums, photographic portraits, scrapbooks (Kreps vacation trips). Includes early family albums, photographs of ancestors, Kreps' childhood, his school and college days, earlyfamily life, etc.
    - Photographs (Box 4)